spartacus-educational.com 2019-11-16

# Privacy Statement

Sections

  * Contacting Spartacus Educational Publishers Ltd 
  * Cookies usage 
  * Website Disclaimer

Spartacus Educational Publisher Ltd. aim to offer a service that is free to all and free to use in a manner that will not infringe any privacy. 

The basic Spartacus Educational website does not use any cookies, but applications utilised on these site do. For example we use Google Analytics, Google AdSense. These are subject to the privacy policies of these companies 

We have summarised some of the main elements where cookies will be used in association with this site below. 

**Collection of website statistics**

For Spartacus Educational, like most standard Web site servers, log files are used to collect Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, and date/time stamp. In addition to this, similar statistics are collected by Google using their Analytics programme. This information is used to analyse the performance of Spartacus Educational website: its usage, it is used to administer the site, understand usage and the overall navigation trends, and determine the relevance of content. This information is not linked to any personally identifiable information. 

The site has implemented the Google Analytics features based on Display Advertising (e.g. Remarketing, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, the DoubleClick Campaign Manager integration or Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting). Using the Ads Settings, visitors can opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customise Google Display Network ads. There are also Google Analytics' available opt outs for the web. 

This site and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimise and serve ads based on someone's past visits to the website. 

The Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, has been implemented. This is used to gain information about the types of visitors (not individuals) that visit the site. It helps us better meet the needs of users and thereby provide a better service. 

##### Contacting Spartacus Educational Publishers Ltd 

Should any user contact Spartacus Educational, the email address will only be used to contact the sender in regard to the original of associated queries. These email addresses will not be passed on to other parties, nor will they be used for advertising. 

##### Cookies usage 

Our website uses cookies like most sites. Cookies are small packets of data that are stored in your web browser. 

Cookies help us to identify information such as how many people are using our website and what devices they are using. This allows us to improve our site for the people who use it. 

You can choose how your browser handles cookies or turn them off entirely by changing your browser settings. This may affect how you see our website and how well it works for you. 

[www.aboutcookies.org ](https://www.aboutcookies.org/) has useful information on how to manage cookies in your browser.

**External Websites**

While Spartacus Educational aims to offer a service that is fair and free from the risk of infringements of individual rights, no guarantees can be made for any site into which Spartacus Educational links either by way in links, advertising or affiliate relationships. When linking out of the site, no guarantees can be made about the privacy policies of these sites. 

We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website visitors; this policy sets out how we will treat your personal information.

(1) What information do we collect?

We may collect, store and use the following kinds of personal data:

1\. Information about your visits to and use of this website;

2\. Information that you provide to us for the purpose subscribing to our email notifications.

(2) Information about website visits

We may collect information about you computer and your visits to this website such as your IP address, geographical location, browser type, referral source, length of visit and number of page views. We may use this information in the administration of this website, to improve the website's usability, and for marketing purposes.

We use cookies on this website. A cookie is a text file sent by a web server to a web browser, and stored by the browser. The text file is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. This enables the web server to identify and track the web browser.

We may send a cookie which may be stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. We may use the information we obtain from the cookie in the administration of this website, to improve the website's usability and for marketing purposes. We may also use that information to recognise your computer when you visit our website, and to personalise our website for you.

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies. (For example, in Internet Explorer you can refuse all cookie by clicking "Tools", "Internet Options", "Privacy", and selecting "Block all cookies" using the sliding selector.) This will, however, have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.

Privacy policies of external organisations

• [Google](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-GB&gl=uk) (Analytics, AdSense, DFP Small Business, etc.)

• [Mailchimp Newsletter](https://kb.mailchimp.com/accounts/management/about-mailchimp-the-eu-swiss-privacy-shield-and-the-gdpr)

(3) Using your personal data

Personal data submitted to this website will be used for the purposes specified in this privacy policy or in relevant parts of the website.

We will not without your express consent provide your personal information to any third parties for the purpose of direct marketing.

(4) Other disclosures

In addition to the disclosures reasonably necessary for the purposes identified elsewhere in this privacy policy, we may disclose information about you:

1\. To the extent that we are required to do so by law;

2\. In connection with any legal proceedings or prospective legal proceedings;

3\. In order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights (including providing information to others for the purposes of fraud prevention and reducing credit risk);

4\. Except as provided in this privacy policy, we will not provide your information to third parties.

(5) Security of your personal data

We will take reasonable precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information. Of course, data transmission over the internet is inherently insecure, and we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the internet.

(6) Policy amendments

We may update this privacy policy from time-to-time by posting a new version on our website. You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes.

(7) Third party websites

The website contains links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies of third party websites.

(8) Our contact details

If you require further information about this matter please email john.simkin@ntlworld.com

This Privacy Policy is based on a freely-available template created and distributed by [www.website-law.co.uk ](http://www.website-law.co.uk/)

##### Website Disclaimer

(1) Introduction

This disclaimer governs your use of our website; by using our website, you accept this disclaimer in full. If you disagree with any part of this disclaimer, do not use our website.

(2) Intellectual property rights

Unless otherwise stated, we or our licensors own the intellectual property rights in the website and material on the website. Subject to the licence below, all our intellectual property rights are reserved.

(3) Licence to use website

You may view, download for caching purposes only, and print pages from the website, provided that:

1\. You must not republish material from this website (including republication on another website), or reproduce or store material from this website in any public or private electronic retrieval system;

2\. You must not reproduce, duplicate, copy, sell, resell, visit, or otherwise exploit our website or material on our website for a commercial purpose, without our express written consent;

(4) Limitations of liability

The information on this website is provided free-of-charge, and you acknowledge that it would be unreasonable to hold us liable in respect of this website and the information on this website.

Whilst we endeavour to ensure that the information on this website is correct, we do not warrant its completeness or accuracy; nor do we not commit to ensuring that the website remains available or that the material on this website is kept up-to-date.

To the maximum extent permitted by applicable law we exclude all representations, warranties and conditions (including, without limitation, the conditions implied by law of satisfactory quality, fitness for purpose and the use of reasonable care and skill).

Our liability is limited and excluded to the maximum extent permitted under applicable law. We will not be liable for any direct, indirect or consequential loss or damage arising under this disclaimer or in connection with our website, whether arising in tort, contract, or otherwise - including, without limitation, any loss of profit, contracts, business, goodwill, reputation, data, income, revenue or anticipated savings.

However, nothing in this disclaimer shall exclude or limit our liability for fraud, for death or personal injury caused by our negligence, or for any other liability which cannot be excluded or limited under applicable law.

(5) Variation

We may revise this disclaimer from time-to-time. Please check this page regularly to ensure you are familiar with the current version.

(6) Entire agreement

This disclaimer constitutes the entire agreement between you and us in relation to your use of our website, and supersedes all previous agreements in respect of your use of this website.

(7) Law and jurisdiction

This notice will be governed by and construed in accordance with English law, and any disputes relating to this notice shall be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts of England.

(8) Our contact details

Please see above for our contact details.

This Privacy Policy is based on a freely-available template created and distributed by [www.website-law.co.uk ](http://www.website-law.co.uk/)
